<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<Module>
  <ModulePrefs title="ROLE Space Microblog"
		description="A widget for real-time microblogging within a ROLE space. Uses ROLE interwidget communication and OpenApp space resource management."
		author="Dominik Renzel"
		author_email="renzel@dbis.rwth-aachen.de"
		height="600">
  	<Require feature="opensocial-0.8" />
    <Require feature="openapp" />
    <OAuth>
		<Service name="openapp" xmlns:openapp="http://www.role-project.eu/xml/openapp/opensocialext/" 
			openapp:service="http://purl.org/role/terms/spaceService"
			openapp:permitReadAppend="http://purl.org/role/terms/data">
			<Request method="" url=""/>
			<Authorization url=""/>
			<Access method="" url=""/>
		</Service>
    </OAuth>
  </ModulePrefs>
  <Content type="html">
    <![CDATA[
		
		<style type="text/css">
			* {
				font-family: Verdana;
				sans-serif; 
				font-size: 8pt;
			}
			
			.ui-widget {
				margin: 5pt;
			}
			
			.ui-widget-content, .ui-widget-header {
				padding: 2pt;
			}
			
			#entries {
				height: 530px;
				overflow: auto;
			}
			
			#input-entry {
				width: 100%;
			}
		</style>
		
		<link rel="stylesheet" href="http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jqueryui/1.8.10/themes/cupertino/jquery-ui.css" type="text/css" media="all" />
		
		<script type="text/javascript" src="https://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jquery/1.7.1/jquery.min.js"></script>
		<script type="text/javascript" src="http://ajax.googleapis.com/ajax/libs/jqueryui/1.8.10/jquery-ui.min.js"></script>
		
		<!-- ROLE IWC: import IWC client definition -->
		<script type="text/javascript" src="http://dbis.rwth-aachen.de/gadgets/iwc/lib/iwc.js"></script>
		  
		<script>
		
			// OpenApp: Maintain current space context as global variable
			var space;
			
			// OpenApp: Maintain the current user context as global variable
			var user;
			
			// OpenApp: Define a namespace for your data
			var microblogns = "http://dbis.rwth-aachen.de/gadgets/microblog/rdf/";
			
			// ROLE IWC: Maintain interwidget communication client connected to space context as global variable
			var iwcClient;
			
			// OpenApp: Initialize space and user context (asynchronously)
			openapp.resource.get(openapp.param.space(), (function(s) {
				
				space = s;
				
				// ROLE IWC: as soon as space context is initialized, initialize IWC client and connect a callback function reacting to incoming intents
				iwcClient = new iwc.Client();
				iwcClient.connect(iwcCallback);
				
				openapp.resource.get(openapp.param.user(), (function(u) {
					user = u;
					
					console.log(openapp.resource.context(u).sub(openapp.ns.role + "data").list());
					renderUI();
				}));
				
			}));
			
			// ROLE IWC: implement a callback function reacting to intents
			function iwcCallback(intent){
				console.log("Microblogging Widget: received intent");
				console.log(intent);
				
				// ROLE IWC: differentiate between different types of intents.
				// In this example we are only interested in those intents having intent.action specified as 'ACTION_UPDATE' and
				// containing an element 'microblog' in intent.categories.
				if(intent.action == "ACTION_UPDATE" && $.inArray("microblog",intent.categories) > -1){
					
					// 
					renderEntry(intent.data);
				}
			}
			
			// This function renders the complete user interface of the widget. This function is called in particular, when the widget is (re)loaded.
			function renderUI(){
				// use jQuery to define a button triggering the publication of a new microblog entry
				$("#button-publish").button().click(function() {
					publishEntry();
				});
			
				// OpenApp: afterwards, retrieve a list of all space data sub-resources of a certain type. 
				// The type is given as a namespace URI, which in this example is given as a custom namespace. 
				var entryList = openapp.resource.context(space).sub(openapp.ns.role + "data").type(microblogns + "entry").list();
				
				// Flush the DOM container element for rendering microblog entries. 
				$("#entries").html("");
				
				// Iterate over the list of all microblog entries.
				for (i = 0; i < entryList.length; i++)  {
					var entry = entryList[i];
					// Render each entry.
					renderEntry(entry.uri);
				};
			}
			
			// This function renders a specific microblog entry given by its resource URI.
			function renderEntry(uri){
				
				//OpenApp: first, we use the microblog entry's URI to fetch its metadata asynchronously (cf. function 'getResourceMetadata').
				getResourceMetadata(uri, function(entryUri,entryProperties){
					
					// OpenApp: then, we use the entry's publisher URI contained in the respective metadata property to get a human-readable name for the entry's publisher, again using function 'getResourceMetadata'.
					getResourceMetadata(entryProperties[openapp.ns.dcterms + "publisher"], function(userUri,userProperties){
						
						// Use jQuery to construct an HTML div element rendering the microblog entry.
						var entryHtml = $("<div class='ui-widget ui-corner-all ui-state-default' id='" + entryUri + "'><div class='ui-widget-header'><a href='" + (entryProperties[openapp.ns.dcterms + "publisher"]) + "/:index'>" + userProperties[openapp.ns.dcterms + "title"] + "</a> (" + entryProperties[openapp.ns.dcterms + "issued"] + ") </div><div class='ui-widget-content'>" + (entryProperties[openapp.ns.dcterms + "abstract"]) + "</div></div>");
						
						// Append the constructed HTML div element to the DOM container element for microblog entries.
						entryHtml.appendTo($("#entries"));
					});
				
				});
			}
			
			// OpenApp: this function is a helper function to retrieve a resource's metadata asynchronously. Its code reveals some of the basic principles on how to work with the OpenApp API.
			// The callback function 'cb' should be a function with two parameters, the first being the resource URI and the second being an associative array of resource metadata properties and their values.
			function getResourceMetadata(uri,cb){
				// OpenApp: first use openapp.resource.get to perform a get operation on the given URI asynchronously. The result is then a context, given as callback parameter 'context'.
				openapp.resource.get(uri, function(context){
					// OpenApp: proceed to work with the resource using the resulting context object in conjunction with the function openapp.resource.context. 
					// In this example, we fetch the given resource's metadata, again performing a get operation asynchronously. The result is again a context, given as callback parameter 'metadata' 
					openapp.resource.context(context).metadata().get(function(metadata){
						// OpenApp: proceed to work with the resource's metadata content using the resulting metadata context in conjunction with the function openapp.resource.content.
						// In this example, we fetch the given resource's metadata properties in form of an associative array and pass resource uri and metadata properties to the callback 'cb' 
						// initially passed to this function.
						cb(metadata.uri,openapp.resource.content(metadata).properties());
					});
				});
			}
			
			// This function is called as soon as somebody pushes the 'Publish' button. First, user input for a blog entry is collected from the UI. Then, the entry is stored as a space data sub-resource. 
			// Finally, on successful storage a ROLE IWC intent is broadcasted to all space members to update their widgets regarding the newly published entry. 
			function publishEntry(){
				
				// OpenApp: within the space context create a new data sub-resource for a new entry typed with the respective namespace (you defined above). 
				openapp.resource.context(space).sub(openapp.ns.role + "data").type(microblogns + "entry").create(function(entry) {
					
					// OpenApp: on successful creation of the entry resource, define semantic metadata as RDF graph 
					var graph = openapp.resource.context(entry).metadata().graph(); 
					
					// OpenApp: define title, creator, and creation date for the new entry using terms from the Dublin Core Metadata Initiative
					// (a full list of all available DCMI terms is available at http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms) 
					// (you can also use any other ontology for your purposes, e.g. FOAF, SIOC.)
					
					graph.literal(openapp.ns.dcterms + "abstract", $("#input-entry").val()); // add entry text from input element as abstract
					graph.literal(openapp.ns.dcterms + "publisher", user.uri); // add URI of the current user as publisher
					graph.literal(openapp.ns.dcterms + "issued", new Date()); // add current time as date of publication
					
					// OpenApp: finally store entry metadata on server
					graph.put(function(){
						// ROLE IWC: on successful entry metadata storage, broadcast an interwidget communication message to notify other space members to update their UIs.  
						notifyResourceUpdate(entry.uri);
					});
				});
			}
			
			// ROLE IWC: this function formulates and then broadcasts a ROLE IWC intent to update the data behind the URI given as parameter to all space members.
			// OpenApp: the URI passed to this function could also be an OpenApp resource URI. In this widget, we make use of this function after successful storage of a microblog entry.
			function notifyResourceUpdate(uri){
				
				// ROLE IWC: formulate an intent; notice that no sender needs to be specified. The ROLE IWC framework will set the sender automatically.
				var intent = {
				  "component": "",
				  "data": uri,
				  "categories": ["microblog"],
				  "dataType": "text/json",
				  "action": "ACTION_UPDATE",
				  "flags"	:["PUBLISH_GLOBAL"]
				};
				
				// ROLE IWC: finally use the ROLE IWC client to publish the intent to the whole space and its members.
				iwcClient.publish(intent);
			}
			
		</script>
		
		<!-- Main widget UI -->
		<div>
			<div class="ui-widget-header">
				<label for="input-entry">New entry:</label><br/> 
				<input type="text" id="input-entry" class='text ui-widget-content ui-corner-all' />
				<button id="button-publish" class="fg-button ui-corner-all">Publish</button>
			</div>
			<div id="entries"></div>
		</div>
		
    ]]>
  </Content>
</Module>
